Kevin Hayes Anderson

Chennai, India | +91 9585652041 | kevinhayesanderson@gmail.com | kevinhayesanderson.github.io

Employment Profile:

Senior software and cloud engineer with 7 years of experience in Agile enterprise software development, cloud architecture, and development in multiple languages and microservices. Proficient in functional, low-level programming and Microsoft Azure Cloud Services. Interested in working with microservices using Rust.

Work History:

Ambigai Consultancy Services India Private Limited, Chennai, India

Dec 2019 - Present

Role: Software Development Lead

Client: Schaeffler

- Developing pre- and post-processors Windows applications for finite element analysis software.
- Building core libraries for calculations in the cloud.
- Build a Native hosting suite to invoke core libraries in a native process from scratch.
- Improved performance in Web services, windows apps and in cloud calculation libraries.

Client: Goldbeck GmbH

• Developing Plugins for the Tekla Structures application.

Tech Stack: Functional Programming, Azure Functions, Azure Service Bus, Azure Storage & Azure DevOps.

Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai, India

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019

Project: Cigna HealthCare Role: .NET Developer

- Migrated legacy VB.NET application to ASP.NET MVC application.
- Developed and maintained backend services.
- Improved performance of batch processing background service.

Project: H&M

Role: Full Stack Developer

- Developed Web APIs for domain services to support microservice architecture.
- Built a test automation suite using Selenium from scratch.
- Developed and maintained web applications built using the ASP.NET MVC framework and Angular.

Tech Stack: Angular, .NET Core, ASP.NET, Microservices, CQRS and RabbitMQ.

Education:

Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering, 8.1/10, Sastra University, Thanjavur, India

2012 - 2016

XII, 93.41/100, RSK HR. SEC. School, Tiruchirappalli, India

2010 - 2011

Skills:

Front-end	Back-end	Windows	Languages	Others
Angular v16	.NET Core,	WPF,	C#, F#, Rust, JavaScript,	Selenium, Git, SQL
	ASP.NET	WinForms	Typescript, Python	Server

Certifications:

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate, Acquired in October 2023. Credential link.

Cloud Developer using Microsoft Azure, Acquired in July 2023. Credential link.

IBM Full Stack Cloud Developer, Acquired in March 2022. Credential link.

Microsoft Technology Associate for Software Development Fundamentals, December 2016. <u>link</u>. Code: nSE6-XVNa And more...